# 大家好 今天來釣魚哦
Hi everyone! Today we come fishing here.
# 你看 這個山 好陡的
Look! This hill, is really steep.
# 這個魚塘在山頂上 和一個小水庫
The pond is at the peak. And there's a reservoir too.
# 我們上去釣
Let's go fishing there.
# 帶了攝影小哥的裝備
These are Mr. Cameraman's gears.
# 帶了把刀
And this is a knife.
# 在這上面
It's up there.
# 這坡太陡啦
The slope is far too steep!
# 走的都兩腿發軟
My legs are already fatigue.
# 終於到了出頂
Finally, we're at the peak now.
# 這裡 好多鯽魚哦 小鯽魚來的
Here, here are a lot of "ji yu" (local carps). These are all small "ji yu".
# 我再去前面看一下
Let me have a look in the front,
# 看有沒有
and see if there's a,
# 好
a,
# 好釣的地方
a good site for fishing.
# 你看 這水好深哦
Look! The water is really deep here.
# 這就是
This is the,
# 把水 多出來的水往這邊排的
the water, the excessive water is discharged to this side.
# 那個山頂上那個水庫啊 不好多釣魚的
The reservoir at the, you know, the peak, is not a good site for fishing.
# 我去那邊 那邊那個
Let me go over there, to the, I mean,
# 魚塘上釣
the pond over there.
# 你看 上面躺著一個人
Look! Somebody is lying up there.
# 那是我兄弟哦
That's my buddy.
# 他在那裡釣魚
He's fishing there.
# 走 我看一下他魚釣有沒有魚
Go! I'm gonna see if there's any fish on his hook.
# 看他睡著了
I think he has fallen asleep.
# 把他的魚帶回家
I can take away his fish.
# 誒誒誒 有魚有魚
Oy, oy oy! Fish, fish!
# 耶
Ye?
# 那麼小的
It's so small.
# 有一條
Here's one.
# 小鯽魚來的
It's a small "ji yu".
# 啊 你看 就搞了一條
Ah, look! So here's one.
# 那麼小的
It's so small,
# 不是很大
not too big.
# 拿袋子來
Let me take a bag.
# 你看 釣了一兩條 哎呦
Look! I have a couple of fish here, ayo!
# 那麼活潑
They're so energetic.
# 你看 這兩條 鯽魚湯
Look! These two, "ji yu" soup.
# 這兩條
These two,
# 拿回去就可以做鯽魚湯
can be used to make a soup.
# 好活潑啊 現在
They're so energetic now.
# 想出去 哪有那麼容易
You wanna flee? You think you can flee away that easily?
# 住在這個網
The net is now your home.
# 就不要想出去了
Don't think that you can ever go out.
# 拿回去 煮點鯽魚湯喝一下
Let's take them back. Then I can enjoy a "ji yu" soup.
# 多久都沒吃過肉了
When is the last time I had meat?
# 幕後花絮
Behind the scene